<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-16T15:53:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">A Familiar Notion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/familiarnotion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Familiar Notion" /><published>2025-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/familiarnotion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/familiarnotion.html"><![CDATA[<p>The life that I live is one shaped by ideas and opinions that I hold. After all, what is life but the small actions I take, tempered by the means by which I have to take them? And, how is it that you suppose those actions are chosen? As such, I regard these ideas and opinions as important—fundamentally so, in fact—and thus a change in them necessitates a good deal of contrary information. Whether or not a change in ideal (if I may call them that) <em>should</em> require hefty evidence against it is perhaps debatable, but not especially pertinent to what I’m trying to say. What I <em>am</em> trying to say is that these changes are not to be taken lightly. A change in ideal is a change of self—permanent and consequential.</p>

<p>And yet, I have on occasion found old, retired ideals cropping up over the horizon on the path of ethical development. It is a strange experience to be faced with those past views. I am almost always wary, hesitant to accept them as I once had. These ideas have no memory of our past—but I do—and the pain of betrayal I once felt from them is not easily forgotten. That said, I do oftentimes come to accept them once more. Whether out of forgiveness or weakness I cannot say, but I am usually happy to have them back.</p>

<p>To help in understanding what I’m trying to describe, I feel like it would be best to draw on some generally shared experience. Take, for example, the rebellious developments of adolescence:</p>

<p>As a child, most are—at least on the more fundamental level to which I speak—obedient to the rules enforced on them. As one grows, they generally begin to desire independence, both of body and mind, and reject those beliefs taken for granted in childhood. They have contemplated some ideal and, upon close inspection, found it to be undesirable.</p>

<p>We all know what comes next. The realities of life set in, and the obstinate rebelliousness of the teen years begins to fade. Within a decade (or sometimes a few) most have settled back into that same comfortable obedience they practiced as children.</p>

<p>Now, a question: Do the adults—in terms of their ideals—differ from the children? I ask this seriously, because from the outside it seems that they have regressed. The teen years felt like an important step—some fundamental change of form—and yet here they are, agreeing with the children. But they’re not <em>really</em> agreeing with the children, are they? There’s a history, a nuance that the children lack. They may be described by the same words, but the ideals which lead the adult’s life are not quite the same as the child’s.</p>

<p>This is what I’ve been finding with my own understanding of the world. This circular pattern of ideas that leads you round and round, seemingly towards unbelieveable and revolutionary ideas, only to drop you off right where you started—but things are a little different, a little more nuanced.</p>

<p>It’s frustrating. It sometimes even feels hopeless. But things do change, and ignorant acceptance is no way to live.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The life that I live is one shaped by ideas and opinions that I hold. After all, what is life but the small actions I take, tempered by the means by which I have to take them? And, how is it that you suppose those actions are chosen? As such, I regard these ideas and opinions as important—fundamentally so, in fact—and thus a change in them necessitates a good deal of contrary information. Whether or not a change in ideal (if I may call them that) should require hefty evidence against it is perhaps debatable, but not especially pertinent to what I’m trying to say. What I am trying to say is that these changes are not to be taken lightly. A change in ideal is a change of self—permanent and consequential.]]></summary></entry></feed>